As a conceptual artist,
كفنان تصوري،
I'm constantly looking for creative ways to spark challenging conversations.
أبحثُ باستمرار على وسائل مبتكرة لإثارة المناقشات الجريئة.
I do this though painting, sculpture, video and performance.
أقوم بذلك عن طريق الرسم والنحت والفيديو والأداء.
But regardless of the format,
ولكن بغض النظر عن الطريقة،
two of my favorite materials are history and dialogue.
فالتاريخ والحوار هما الموضوعين المفضلين عندي.
In 2007, I created "Lotus,"
في 2007، صنعتُ "لوتس"،
a seven-and-a-half-foot diameter,
بقطر سبع أقدام و نصف،
600-pound glass depiction of a lotus blossom.
لوحة رسم زجاجية زنتها 600 رطل من زهر اللوتس،
In Buddhism, the lotus is a symbol for transcendence
في البوذية، يرمزُ اللوتس إلى التفوق والسمة والرفعة
and for purity of mind and spirit.
وإلى نقاء العقل والروح.
But a closer look at this lotus
ولكن بنظرة أعمق لهذا اللوتس
reveals each petal to be the cross-section of a slave ship.
تكشفُ كل بتلة عن المقطع العرضي لسفينة الرقيق.
This iconic diagram was taken from a British slaving manual
أُخذ هذا الرسم الرمزي من دليل الرق البريطاني
and later used by abolitionists to show the atrocities of slavery.
واستخدم لاحقاً من قبل دعاة تحرير العبودية لإظهار همجية العبودية.
In America, we don't like to talk about slavery,
في أمريكا، لا نحبُ الحديث عن العبودية.
nor do we look at it as a global industry.
ولا ننظرُ إليها كصناعة عالمية كذلك،
But by using this Buddhist symbol,
ولكن بإستعمال هذا الرمز اليوذي،
I hope to universalize and transcend
آملُ في تعميم وتجاوز
the history and trauma of black America
تاريخ ومعاناة السود الأمريكيين.
and encourage discussions about our shared past.
وتشجيع النقاشات حول ماضينا المشترك.
To create "Lotus," we carved over 6,000 figures.
لصُنع "اللوتس"، نقشنا أكثر من 6،000 شكل،
And this later led to a commission by the City of New York
وقاد ذلك لاحقاً إلى تكليفنا من قبل مدينة نيويورك
to create a 28-foot version in steel
لصُنع نسخة فولاذية بقطر 28 قدم
as a permanent installation at the Eagle Academy for Young Men,
كتنصيب شعار دائم في أكاديمية النسر للناشئين من البنين،
a school for black and latino students,
مدرسة للطلاب السود واللاتينيين،
the two groups most affected by this history.
المجموعتين الاكثر تضرراً بهذا التاريخ.
The same two groups are very affected by a more recent phenomenon,
نفس هاتين المجموعتين تتأثران بشدة من ظاهرة أكثر حداثة،
but let me digress.
لكن إسمحوا لي أن أبتعد عن الموضوع.
I've been collecting wooden African figures
كنتُ أجمعُ أشكالاً خشبية الصنع تابعة للأفارقة
from tourist shops and flea markets around the world.
من المحلات السياحية والبازارات حول العالم.
The authenticity and origin of them is completely debatable,
مصدر وأصالة هذه الأشياء مُختلف ومتنازع عليه تماماً،
but people believe these to be imbued with power,
لكن يعتقدُ الناس أن هذه الأشياء مصبوغة و مشبعة بالقوة،
or even magic.
أو حتى السحر.
Only recently have I figured out how to use this in my own work.
اكتشفتُ فقط مؤخرًا كيف أتمكن من استخدام هذا في عملي الخاص.
(Gun shots)
(عيارات نارية لبندقية)
Since 2012, the world has witnessed the killings of Trayvon Martin,
منذ 2012، شهد العالم مقتل تريفن مارتن،
Michael Brown, Eric Garner, Sandra Bland, Tamir Rice
ومايكل براون واريك غارنر، وساندرا بلاند وتامير رايس
and literally countless other unarmed black citizens
وعدد آخر لا يحصى من المواطنين السود العُزّل وغير المسلحين
at the hands of the police,
على يد أفراد الشرطة،
who frequently walk away with no punishment at all.
الذين غالباً ما يمضوا دون عقاب على الإطلاق.
In consideration of these victims
وبأحذ هؤلاء الضحايا بالإعتبار
and the several times that even I,
وفي عدة مرات كنتُ حتى،
a law-abiding, Ivy League professor,
أستاذ يحترم القانون في رابطة اللبلاب،
have been targeted and harassed at gunpoint by the police.
تم استهدافي ومضايقتي تحت تهديد السلاح من قبل أفراد الشرطة.
I created this body of work simply entitled "BAM."
صنعتُ هذا المجسم وأطلقتُ عليه إسم "بام".
It was important to erase the identity of each of these figures,
كان من المهم طمر شخصية كل هذه الأشكال،
to make them all look the same and easier to disregard.
لجعلهم متشابهين في الشكل وأسهل للتجاهل.
To do this, I dip them in a thick, brown wax
للقيام بذلك، غمستهم في شمع بُني كثيف السماكة
before taking them to a shooting range
قبل أخذهم إلى ساحة الرماية.
where I re-sculpted them using bullets.
حيثُ أعدتُ نحتهم باستخدام الطلقات النارية.
And it was fun,
وكان ذلك ممتعاً،
playing with big guns and high-speed video cameras.
اللعب ببنادق كبيرة وكاميرا فيديو عالية السرعة،
But my reverence for these figures kept me from actually pulling the trigger,
ولكن تقديري وإحترامي لهذه الأشكال أبعدني فعلاً عن الضغط على الزناد،
somehow feeling as if I would be shooting myself.
كان الشعور بطريقة أو بأخرى كما لو أنني سأقتل نفسي،
Finally, my cameraman, Raul, fired the shots.
وفي النهاية، أطلق مصوري الشخصي "راؤول" العيارات النارية.
I then took the fragments of these
وأخذتُ لاحقاً بقايا من هذه
and created molds, and cast them first in wax,
وشكّلتُ قوالب وسبكتهم أولاً في الشمع،
and finally in bronze like the image you see here,
وأخيراً في البرونز مثل هذه الصورة التي ترونها هنا،
which bears the marks of its violent creation
التي تحملُ علامات صُنعها القاسي
like battle wounds or scars.
مثل آثار نُدب وجروح معركة.
When I showed this work recently in Miami,
عندما عرضتُ هذا العمل في ميامي،
a woman told me she felt every gun shot to her soul.
قالت امرأة لي: أنها شعرت أنّ كل طلقة نارية موجهه إلى روحها.
But she also felt that these artworks
ولكنها شعرت أيضاً أن هذه الأعمال الفنية
memorialized the victims of these killings
تُحيي ذكرى ضحايا عمليات القتل هذه
as well as other victims of racial violence throughout US history.
فضلاً عن غيرهم من ضحايا العنف العنصري على مدى تاريخ أمريكا.
But "Lotus" and "BAM" are larger than just US history.
لكن "لوتس" و "بام" أكبر من مجرد تاريخ للولايات المتحدة.
While showing in Berlin last year,
أثناء عرضهم في برلين السنة الماضية،
a philosophy student asked me what prompted these recent killings.
سألني طالب فلسفة: ما الذي دفع إلى مثل هذه الإغتيالات الأخيرة.
I showed him a photo of a lynching postcard
أريته صورة بطاقة بريدية للإعدام الغوغائي-
from the early 1900s
تعود لبدايات سنوات التسعينات
and reminded him that these killings have been going on for over 500 years.
وذكّرته أن هذه الإغتيالات مستمرة منذ أكثر من 500 عام.
But it's only through questions like his
ولكن فقط من خلال أسئلة مثل سؤاله
and more thoughtful dialogue about history and race
والمزيد من الحوار الجدّي الأكثر عمقاً حول التاريخ والعِرق
can we evolve as individuals and society.
يُمكننا الرقي كأفراد ومجتمعات.
I hope my artwork creates a safe space
آملُ أن يخلق عملي الفني مجالاً آمناً
for this type of honest exchange
لهذا النوع من التبادل الصادق
and an opportunity for people to engage one another
وفرصة للناس لمشاركة بعضهم البعض
in real and necessary conversation.
في نقاشات ومحادثات ضرورية و حقيقية.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)